本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： Nothing 小坏玩意儿 弥尔
校对： 海之南   后期： 海之南
舞蹈学院 前情提要
Previously on Dance Academy...
停 收工
Cut! Print!
各位 凯特莉娜・卡拉马科夫的拍摄活动完美谢幕
Everybody, that is a wrap on Katrina Karamakov!
奥利 你是来结交关系的呢 还是来和我约会的
Ollie, are you here to network or to hang out with me?
这很重要 关及我的事业
This is my career. It's important.
马库斯 你求婚了
Marcus, you put a ring on it!
你们是都准备搬去德克萨斯州吗
Are you all planning on moving to Texas?
- 无视我好了 - 又没起效果
- Ignore me. - Zero impact again!
你的背一有好转 你要跳我为你选的独舞
When your back improves, you'll do the solo I selected for you.
我会继续和赛斯吉娅合作 从她那儿我学到很多
I'm going to keep working with Saskia. I'm learning a lot from her.
游戏开始了 塔拉・韦伯斯特 游戏开始
Game on, Tara Webster. Game on.
舞蹈学院 第三季第12集
这真难理解
It's hard to comprehend
明晚我将要去参加国家芭蕾舞团的试镜
tomorrow night I'll be auditioning for the National Ballet Company.
这是我们最后一次以学生的身份跳舞了
The final time we dance as students.
过去三年的高潮部分
The culmination of the past three years.
注意 不要太张扬
Careful! Don't oversell it.
能给我一个幸运三叶草吗
Do I get a special clover?
我不用参加舞团试镜 但今晚是我的全球首映
I don't have a company audition, but it is my world premiere.
如果电影很糟糕呢
What if the movie sucks?
如果我演得很烂 人们向我丢东西呢 比如很锋利的东西
What if I suck and people throw things - sharp things?
每个人都会得到三叶草 连格瑞斯都有
Everyone gets a clover, even Grace.
我要把以积极的心态结束这一学年当做我的使命
I'm making it my mission to end the year on a positive note.
不仅是为了积善
And not just to get my karma points up
以使宇宙奖励我一份合同
so the universe rewards me with a contract.
那会显得我...
That would make me...
你是个冷酷无情的战士
You're a cold, ruthless warrior.
这些人自以为他们把你那好胜的骨髓给抽走了
These people think they've sucked you of your competitive marrow?
证明他们是错的 打倒他们
Prove them wrong. Take them down.
舞团能把我俩都招进去吗
Could the company take both of us?
他比我更应得这个
He still deserves it more than I do.
他饰演的王子比我的更梦幻
His prince is dreamier than mine.
这是基佬思想还是嫉妒思想
Is that a gay thought or a jealous thought?
当然是嫉妒思想了
Jealous thought. Definitely.
他是个骗子 什么技术都没有
He's a fraud, a mere blow-in.
得了 不要再扮礼貌了 拿出点行动 伙计
Sheesh, stop being polite and make a move, buddy.
我才不迷信
I'm not superstitious...
世界上没有运气这个东西
there's no such thing as luck.
奥利弗 做了点调查 麦克白的诅咒是很强劲的
Oliver, did some research. The Macbeth curse is potent.
我真怀疑你的幸运毛衣都救不了你
I doubt even your lucky cardigan can save you.
不是幸运
It's not lucky.
是情感
It's sentimental.
因为如果我相信运气了
Because if I believe in luck,
我得去相信我已经倒霉很久了
I have to believe I've been unlucky for a very long time.
我想现在 我们都有各自的焦虑
I guess right now, we all have our own hang-ups.
简直有千万个想法在我们的脑海里奔腾
Literally a thousand thoughts are running through our heads.
最难接受的是 接下来发生的事情是我们无法掌控的
The hardest one to accept... what happens next is out of our hands.
我预测四颗星
I'm predicting four stars.
明天我们在课前跳个致谢舞怎么样
What about a thankyou dance at the start of class tomorrow?
我们全部参与一个精心编排的颂词
We all launch into a choreographed tribute?
一点创意都没有
Negative points for originality.
拜托 这是我们最后一堂课
Oh come on, this is our last class.
雷恩老师要搬去奥斯汀舞团了 这是一个时代的尽头
Miss Raine's moving to Austin. It's the end of an era.
我们得告诉她我们有多感谢她
We have to show her how much she's appreciated.
我很确信她能应付 你们对她来说只是学生
Pretty sure she'll cope. You're all just students to her.
嘘 好戏开始了
Shh! Showtime.
这部地方电影出彩的是
What's great about this local film
它采取了一种被荒废的类型 舞蹈电影
is that it takes a tired genre, the dance movie,
使得故事真挚而有深度
and gives it real heart and depth.
更不用提莱斯・奥利瑞
And not to mention Rhys O'Leary.
谁会预料表演那般精彩
Who would have predicted that performance?
我觉得他和新人凯特莉娜・卡拉马科夫之间的火花
I thought his chemistry with newcomer Kat Karamakov
非常强烈
was particularly strong.
她的确是新人 是吧 是有这么一些时候
She is very new, isn't she? I mean, there were some moments.
表演略显笨拙 但总体来说还是十分入戏的
That were a bit clunky, but overall I thought it was thoroughly engaging.
我也这么觉得 我给四颗星
Oh, so did I. I'm giving it four stars.
我也是 四颗星
Me too. Four stars.
- 四颗星 - 我女朋友十分入戏
- Four stars! - Oooh, my girlfriend's thoroughly engaging.
我称之为"放弃前夕焦虑综合症"
I'm calling it 'impending abandonment anxiety'.
快看 莎拉・维斯塔里尼 第一个被我弄哭的学生
Oh, look! Sarah Vistarini. First student I ever made cry.
什么时候想去奥斯汀和我们住
Any time you want to move to Austin to live with us,
我们随时欢迎你
we'd love to have you.
你们是新婚夫妇 我在会打扰到你们频繁的欢好时光
You'll be newlyweds. I'd be in the way of all that constant nakedness.
- 格瑞斯 - 以那副画面惩罚我自己了
- Grace! - Punish myself with the image.
好吧 相信我 这是个自私的提议
Yeah, well, believe me, it is a selfish offer.
即便不是因为露西
Even if Lucy wasn't a factor,
我的舞团还是会很渴望招到你 所以考虑一下吧
my company would still be angling to get you, so think about it.
好 在一个像今天这样美好的早晨
OK, he would be calling them alarmist
他会叫他们杞人忧天者
on a morning like this,
但是气象局已经发布了一个恶劣天气预警
but the Bureau of Meteorology has issued a severe weather alert
预测中午的天气会突变 伴随暴雨与强风
predicting a midday change, with strong winds and heavy rain.
娱乐新闻方面 大明星莱斯・奥利瑞
And in entertainment news, Rhys O'Leary is in town
来宣传他的新近献礼"彩虹之上"
to promote his latest offering Over The Rainbow.
明星们会出席该电影的全球首...
The stars will be at the film's world prem...
他是你爸 这还不足以让你发条短信吗
He's your dad. Is it not worth a quick text?
我们的关系还没好到发短信
We didn't leave things on texting terms.
但你要毕业了 他还是想来的
But you're graduating! He'd still wanna be here.
现在我能说出这样的话算不算很解放
Isn't it liberating that I can say stuff like that
因为我不是你女朋友
now that I'm not your girlfriend,
也不是潜在女友 也不是心碎的前女友
or potential girlfriend, or heartbroken ex?
过去我也没阻止过你
Didn't stop you in the past.
所以你就这样准备你的试镜吗
So, this is how you're gonna prepare for your audition?
父子奇迹言和 致谢舞
Father-son miracles, thankyou dances.
我只是希望上台的时候 一切都
I just don't wanna go on stage until everything's...
很完美
Perfect.
你不能把整个学业经历简化成一个鞠躬
You can't wrap the entire academy experience up into a bow.
现在是时候抱着必胜的信念了
It's time to want to win.
被诅咒了
Cursed!
我们有着不同的生殖器[性别不同]
You and I have different genitalia.
我又不是你的竞争对手 你干嘛还要在精神上排挤我
I'm not your competition, so why are you trying to psych me out?
这能让我冷静 就跟冥想一样
It's calming. Like meditation.
我能轻易为你争取一个试镜机会
I can easily get you an audition,
而且这对我们明年的家庭团聚也是件好事
and it would be good for us to have some family comforts next year.
露西厨艺不精 但看她涂上嘴唇
Lucy is not the greatest cook, but watch her wax her upper lip.
我满脑子都是国家芭蕾舞团
I can only think about the National.
奥斯汀甚至都挤不进前五
After that, Austin doesn't even make top five.
我们要确保舞团和我们两个都签约
We need to make sure that the company is a lock for both of us.
最后一课
Last class.
好了 够了
Alright, that's enough.
扶好扶手杠 就像过去三年的每一天一样
To the barre, like you've done every day for the past three years.
瞧见没 注意这线条
See? Note the T-cut.
锻炼锁骨与肘部之间的角度 别撅嘴
You wanna work the collarbone to the elbow, minimise the duck face.
这都是弄虚作假 掩盖我有多糟糕
This is all just window dressing to disguise how much I clunked.
别因为一点负面评价就缺席自己的电影首映
One comment does not make you ditch your own movie premiere.
奥利弗 难道我不该去剧院力挺你们吗
Oliver! Don't you think I should be at the theatre supporting you guys?
无所谓 我的其他戏服放在衣柜里都缩水了
I don't care. Wardrobe somehow shrunk my other costume.
我能看看吗
Can I pull this off?
嗨
Hi.
我正打算留言 祝今晚的首映礼顺利
Uh, I was gonna message. Good luck with the premiere tonight.
你试试这两件
You are trying on these and these.
原来传言是真的
Grapevine's accurate, then.
她想让舞团更现代化
She's pushing the company more contemporary.
是啊 意味着她不会喜欢我扮演的白马王子
Yeah, which means she'll hate my Prince Charming.
有一点你说错了 那就是我们才华横溢
The thing you get all twisted up on is that we're the talent.
她需要我们
She needs us.
我还有一场面试
I do have an interview to get to.
当然 我们不是要上演一场争夺战啥的
Of course, and, hey, we're not trying to start a bidding war or anything.
只是想让你知道
We just felt it was respectful for you to know
别的舞团也想和我们签约
that there are other companies getting a tad poachy.
听上去不错 恭喜
That must be very flattering. Congratulations.
但我们坚定选择贵舞团
Oh, but we're committed to this company.
我打算纹一个"我爱国家芭蕾舞团"
I'm getting tattooed 'I love the National'...
它在我们的考虑范围内 但我们想知道
Well, it's on the shortlist, although it's hard to know for sure
贵公司的签约条件 看看自己是否符合要求
until we have an idea of your plans for the company,
才能做决定
how we might fit in.
你们想在试镜之前知道签约条件
You two want to know what's on offer before you deign to audition?
作为前任冠军 我有很多选择
Well, as the pre champion, I do have options,
我们还是一揽子交易
and we are a package deal.
好的 我记住了
Well, I'll keep that front of mind, then.
她被我们征服了
Hooked and gagging for us!
她会觉得我们目中无人
She thinks we think we're too good for the company!
人们需要有所追求才会有所收获
People need to chase to know they want something,
我要去争取 这样我们才能在一起
and I'm wrangling it so that we can stay together.
但我们现在不在一起 只不过一起策划了几次报复活动
But we're not together now! We revenge-pashed a couple of times!
这都是你难以捉摸的思想在作怪
This is all the freaky workings of your head!
- 本 - 别烦我
- Ben... - No, stay away from me!
排练室都满了 你还要练多久
All the studios are booked. How long do you think you'll be?
我不介意一起练
I don't mind sharing.
怎么穿这件 我以为你扮演的是珀尔塞福涅
What's with the costume? I thought you were doing Persephone.
宙斯之女 被冥王劫持娶作冥后
珀尔塞福涅是很漂亮
Persephone's beautiful,
但雷恩老师认为火鸟更戏剧化
but Miss Raine thinks Firebird is more dramatic,
我背上的伤不痛了 所以
and my back's not hurting, so...
我打算辞演白马王子
I'm just about to ditch Prince Charming.
什么 但这角色是为你量身定做的
What? But that role may as well have been invented for you.
他们会说克里斯提的白马王子更时髦
They'll say Christian's Prince is edgier,
而且我还在练一个现代舞 以防万一
and I have a contemporary piece I've been working on, in case.
要不我看你跳给你提意见 然后你看我跳
Well, why don't I watch you and give you feedback, and you watch me,
我们假装没有彻底诀别 紧急关头交换意见
and we'll both pretend we're not cracked, switching last minute?
本 是我 我不想破坏你的舞蹈生涯
Ben, it's me, the person who hasn't ruined your career
所以我来弥补
because I am going to fix this!
再来一次
Go again.
还要来吗
Should I do it again?
看 安然无恙 我鄙视你所谓的诅咒
Here, intact, I spit on your alleged curse.
艾比盖尔・阿姆斯特朗
Abigail Armstrong?
希望不要是花
Better not be flowers.
我明确告诉妈妈和韦斯不要干扰我
I explicitly told Mum and Wes no distractions.
我才不会被打动 谢谢
I will not be humanised. Thank you.
是韦斯
Wes.
你没事吧 噎着了吗
Are you OK? Are you choking?
我要做什么
What do I... do?
- 你还好吗 - 不
- Are you OK? - No!
我果真中邪了 我得走了
I am superstitious, and I have to go.
去哪儿
Where?
- 我去拿我的幸运毛衣 - 什么 奥利
- I need my lucky cardigan. - What?! Ollie!
他有些过于兴奋了
He's a little bit overexcited,
别担心 我都严格地嘱咐过他了
but don't worry, I've given him strict instructions.
只能轻轻地鼓掌 太遗憾了
Polite applause only, which is a real shame,
因为我一直在练习"塔拉小可爱"加油声
because I've been practicing my 'Tara Banana' shout-out.
克里斯提 谢谢你的邀请
Christian! Hey. Thanks for the invite.
- 爸爸妈妈 这是拉弗・里德 - 你好
- Uh, Mum, Dad, this is Raf Reed. - Hi.
你好
Hi. G'day.
如果你想让我离开就告诉我 我不想干扰你
You tell me if you want me to go. I don't want to distract you.
不 我没想到你会来
No, I... I didn't think you would want to come.
开玩笑 这是我第一次看芭蕾
Are you kidding? This is my first ballet.
希望你们喜欢这部电影
I hope you enjoy the movie.
来吧 笑一个
Come on, smile, smile!
和莱斯・奥利瑞合作什么感觉 你崇拜他吗
What was it like working with Rhys O'Leary? Were you starstruck?
放松 微笑
It's alright, smile.
- 凯特 看这边 - 放松 放松
- Kat, over here! - Just relax, relax.
快结束了 保持微笑
It's almost over. Just smile away.
你没在笑
You're not smiling.
我 我打算在这儿趴一会儿
I'm just... I'm gonna stay down here for a while.
尊敬的来宾
Distinguished guests,
国家芭蕾舞团的艺术总监瑞贝卡・布雷斯韦特
artistic director of the National Ballet Company Rebecca Braithwaite,
老师们 同学们 家长们 朋友们 女士们和先生们
teachers, students, parents, friends, ladies and gentlemen,
欢迎莅临今年的毕业典礼
welcome to this year's graduating class.
在今晚的演出之前 请允许我
I'd like to begin tonight's performance
介绍一下克里斯提・里德
by introducing Christian Reed,
出演灰姑娘中的白马王子
dancing Prince Charming from Cinderella.
破坏演出服 一如往昔
Costume sabotage. Takes me back.
抱歉 能否暂停一下音乐
Sorry, can we, uh... can we stop the music for a second?
我的一位好友
A good friend of mine has been trying to figure out
试图找寻最佳的方式来感谢舞蹈学院
the right way to say thank you to the Academy.
可是没有任何一种方式
But it's impossible,
足以回报学院以及你们所有人
because we can never repay what it has given us.
给予我们的一切
What you've all given us.
我不是个演说家 让我用舞蹈来表达吧
So, I'm not a speechmaker. I should probably dance now.
我也不喜欢自己在荧幕上的样子 但我还是会看
I loathe watching myself on screen too, but I do it anyway.
还有什么方面你想要提高演技的
How else are you gonna hone your craft?
没想那么多 反正我只是到演艺圈打个酱油就会离开的
Not a pressing concern, as this will be my only acting foray, so...
哦 太笨拙了
Yeah. Clunky!
不止笨拙 我演得太烂了
Clunky is too generous! I'm horrific!
从臀部两腿外翻
Turn out from the hips...
怎么会烂到这么令人难以置信
How is that there even remotely believable?
- 我不再羞涩了 - 你别再...
- I'm not ashamed anymore. - You're never gonna...
试映期间 你应该来洛杉矶
You should come to LA for pilot season.
我会把你介绍给我的经纪人
I'm gonna hook you up with my manager.
我还有"微不足道"的第三年学业要完成 记得吗
I just have this little thing called third year.
哦 我嘟嘴了 哦 不
Oh! Oh, I'm duck-facing! Oh, no!
奥利发私信给我求救 说他没带手机 被反锁在休息室了
Hey, Ollie's just tweeted me, 'SOS, no phone, stuck in boarding house.'
有人特别渴望得到关注呢
Someone's starved for attention.
还关注着奥利的微博呀
So, still following Ollie's tweets, huh?
全体出动 救人去
All move to the rescue!
本杰明・狄克尔准备上台 三十秒倒计时
Benjamin Tickle to the stage. 30 seconds.
坚持住 亲爱的 我们会救你出来的
Hold tight, precious. We're gonna bust you out.
别费劲了 一切都很明了
Don't bother. The universe has been clear.
我注定签不成约 我没那么幸运
I am not fated to get a contract. I am not the lucky one.
不能如你所愿了
That's disappointing.
你怎么不告诉我 试镜演出这天
You need to tell me that on the day of the auditions,
你和本都已决定要换舞蹈呢
you and Ben have decided to change dances?!
我知道我去找赛斯吉娅的事情让你不高兴
I knew you were upset that I went to Saskia.
我应该相信你的判断
I should have trusted your judgment.
不 是时候相信你自己了
No, it's time to trust your own.
学生总会青出于蓝而胜于蓝
Students outgrow their teachers.
这是必然的 只是老师们还是会不愿面对这个事实
It's natural, but it can still be difficult for us to accept.
我不会...这怎么可能呢
I would never... That could never happen.
这说明你已经准备好了
It means you're ready.
现在 该上台演绎你的珀尔塞福涅了
Now, it's time for you to go on stage as Persephone,
珀尔塞福涅是史特拉汶斯基的一部芭蕾舞剧 讲述希腊神话中的冥后的故事
我知道 如果你能倾情舞出真我
and if you dance it the way I know you can,
那么你的未来 一定是璀璨夺目的
your future, it's written in the stars.
我支持你 虽然这不符合竞争原则 不过...
I had your back, which goes against all competitive logic, however...
你支持我 却弄坏我的演出服
You had my back, yet you destroyed my costume?!
格瑞斯干的
Grace destroyed it.
我特意没告诉她你换成跳火鸟了
I neglected to tell her that you'd switched to Firebird.
- 我刚决定跳回这个了 - 哦噢 糟糕咯
- I just switched back!-  Well, whoops.
你霉运上身了
You are cursed!
不要 它差点砸掉我们的脑袋
No. It could have decapitated us.
我是不是应该停止抱怨上天不给我想要的东西
How about I stop blaming the world for not giving me what I want,
而直接去争取呢
and just take it already?
听起来很有道理
Sounds pretty intelligent to...
塔拉・韦伯斯特 一分钟倒计时
Tara Webster, this is your one-minute call.
嘿
Hey. Hey.
看看你 没什么能阻碍你的
Look at you. Nothing sticks!
我得走了
I've gotta go.
你知道吗 我这一年以来都期待同一件事情
You know the one thing I've looked forward to all year
就是阻止你签约进舞团
is stopping you from getting into the company?
格瑞斯 我不想听这些 你不是这样的人
I'm not listening, Grace. You're better than this.
你总是这么一副屈尊降贵的样子
Always with the condescension!
因为我们曾经是朋友 所以我知道你不是这样的人
You are, I know you are, because you and I were friends once.
我背受伤的时候 你是那么忠诚的朋友
You were so loyal when I broke my back.
可你却把我当成可有可无的人
And you treated me like I was disposable!
我愿意付出所有努力修补我们之间的关系 我真的愿意
I would give anything to make things right between us. I really would.
我是农场主的女儿
I'm a farmer's daughter.
我知道种植庄稼的时候 尽管你做出了所有的努力
I know you can plant the crop and do all the work,
还是要靠老天的恩赐
but the weather has the final word.
大自然的力量
Those forces of nature bigger than you
远远超越你能控制的范围
that can't be controlled.
父亲曾经给我讲过完美风暴形成的过程
Dad explained to me once how a perfect storm is created,
那是许多无关痛痒的事件同时发生
that a combination of harmless events occurring together
共同作用而产生的灾难性的结果
conspire to produce an outcome that is disastrous.
如果不是这粒珠子
If not for a bead.
如果我第一个跳
If I'd danced first.
或者最后一个跳
Or last.
或者根本不跳
Or not at all.
如果我的背没有折裂过
If my back wasn't already fractured.
塔拉 你还好吗
Tara, you OK?
- 我的腿没有知觉了 - 塔拉
- I can't feel my legs. - Tara?
塔拉
Tara?
没有知觉了...
I can't feel my...
好了 大家请散开 请散开
OK, guys, move away, move away, please.
阿比盖尔 叫救护车
Abigail, ambulance.
你会没事的
You're gonna be OK.
你能捏一下我的手吗 就是这样
Can you squeeze my hand? That's it.
- 天哪 我的腿没有知觉了 - 你会没事的
- Oh, my God, I can't feel them... - You're gonna be fine.
你会没事的
It's gonna be OK.
你可以说这是偶然 运气不好 或是我命中注定
It really doesn't matter if you call it random chance, bad luck, my fate.
而这一切发生与否
The difference between everything and nothing
都取决于那些"如果"
comes down to 'if', 'if', 'if'.